#### PERSONAL INFORMATION

# José Carlos Lozano Acevedo

Pinsenada, Baja California, México. P.C. 22890

**\** 177 90 46 **\** (646) 171 76 88

Gender Masculine | Date of birth 09/29/1995 | Nationality Mexican

Portfolio: Click to visualize



#### **PROFILE**

Programming languages

**JavaScript** 

HTML

CSS

Visual Basics Analysis

- I'm a self-thought person with a useful level of knowledge in the above areas. I've been focusing mainly in JavaScript because of how easy is to achieve tasks and how wide the information is spread through the internet. Having HTML and CSS as my structure tools.

I discovered my passion in the developing field when I encounter myself trying to find a way to adapt an old process they had in my current job, because it lacked of structure and sustainability. I saw an opportunity to create something useful from scratch. So, I initiated doing my research and started building an interactive data base for my coworkers and I, to keep track of our daily workload. It helps us coordinate what to focus everyday and let our managers know what we require on a daily basis.

I realized I want to keep on doing this kind of work and now I find myself learning and digging more and more in this field every day.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

November 2023 – Actual Position So

Software QA Engineer (Remote)

Dilato InfoTech, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

April 2022 – November 2023

Licensing Brand Coordinator

Mad Engine/Fortune fashions, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

September 2021 – February 2022

Remote service Bilingual Agent

Teleperformance, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

November 2020 - June 2021

Maintenance Engineer

Rapid Manufacturing, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

November 2019 – November 2020

Maintenance Technician

Rapid Manufacturing, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

February 2019 – November 2019

Electronic technician

GES Returns, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

September 2018 – December 2018

Professional practices

CICESE, Electronics and Telecommunications, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

June 2016 - July 2018

Computer technician

Computación digital, Ensenada Baja California, Mexico.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### August 2014 - December 2018

#### Electronic engineer

#### Universidad Autónoma de Baja California (UABC)

Ensenada, Baja California, México.

- Analog electronics
- Digital electronics
- Power electronics
- System programming (C++, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Python, MATLAB, Variety of PICs)
- Circuit analysis

## August 2011 - June 2014

#### Electronic technician

Centro De Bachillerato Tecnológico, Industrial y de Servicios #41 Ensenada, Baja California, México.

#### PERSONAL SKILLS

#### Main language

Spanish

# Other languages English - 90%

COMPREHENSION		SPEAKING		WRITING
Auditive comprehension	Lecture comprehension	Oral interaction	Oral expression	
C2	C2	C1	C1	C1

#### **TOEFLITP**

Listening Comprehension: 63 Structure & Written Expression: 59 Reading Comprehension: 61 Total score: 610/670

Level: A1/A2: Basic user - B1/B2: Independent user - C1/C2: Competent user Common European Framework of Reference for Languages

#### Communication skills

- Good communication skills acquired during my experience as a computer technician since it
  was required to be involved in a fluid conversation with the client to identify all possible issues with que
  equipment.
- Similarly, these skills have been reinforced by sharing and debating ideas based on continuous improvement on the companies I've worked in.

# Organizational / management skills

- Responsibility (Finish my work in time and if it's possible even before its due time accomplishing everything that was asked for)
- Teamwork (Cooperating with my team to achieve the best possible results)
- Leadership (I always seek to carry out the best proposed ideas, with the support of my coworkers)
- Organization (I keep my work area organized and clean so that I can have a better control of all the elements around in order to have a more fluid development of my work)

#### Extra skills

 Microsoft Office management (Word, Excel, Power Point...)